<!--
  Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
  or more contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file
  distributed with this work for additional information
  regarding copyright ownership.  The ASF licenses this file
  to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
  "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
  with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

  http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  under the License.
-->

<node>
    <name>TermsOfUse</name>
    <property>
        <name>title</name>
        <value>Terms of Use</value>
        <type>String</type>
    </property>
    <property>
        <name>version</name>
        <value>2022-01-01</value>
        <type>String</type>
    </property>
    <property>
        <name>text</name>
        <value>
These terms and conditions (the "Agreement") for a symptoms survey located at datapro.uhn.ca and any associated website, portal, or similar service (collectively, the "Application"), constitute a legal agreement and is entered into by and between you ("you", "your") and the University Health Network ("UHN", "we", "us", "our").  

**IMPORTANT! BY USING OR ACCESSING THE APPLICATION, YOU AGREE TO BECOME BOUND BY THE AGREEMENT. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THE AGREEMENT, YOU MUST NOT USE OR ACCESS THE APPLICATION. NOTE THAT THERE ARE ALTERNATIVE METHODS TO COMPLETE THE SURVEY IF YOU WOULD NOT LIKE TO PROCEED WITH THIS APPLICATION.**  

This Agreement governs your access to the Application and use, including any content, functionality, and services offered on or through the Application.  

The Application is intended to act as an information collection tool for physicians to better prepare for appointments with patients and to improve record keeping. The Application is intended to facilitate symptom reporting to healthcare providers, for quality monitoring and improvement, and general patient education relative to symptom status. It is not a medical device. Nothing contained in the Application should be construed, directly or indirectly, as the practice of medicine or providing medical advice or medical services by UHN. The Application is not intended to diagnose, cure, mitigate, treat, or prevent disease or other conditions.  

**Not Medical Advice.** The App is not a substitute for professional medical advice, diagnosis or treatment. Never make changes to your medication, nor adjust your dose, without first consulting your health care provider. Always seek the advice of a physician or other qualified healthcare provider concerning questions you have regarding a medical condition, and before starting, stopping or modifying any treatment or medication. Never delay obtaining medical advice or disregard medical advice because of something you have or have not read on the App. If you have, or suspect you have, a health problem, or if you experience an adverse side effect, please consult your doctor. If you have, or suspect you are experiencing a health emergency, please call 911 and/or promptly visit a Hospital Emergency Department in your area.  

**No Regulatory Approval.** The App has not been evaluated by Health Canada, the United States Food and Drug Administration (**USFDA**) or any other domestic or foreign regulatory agency and is not approved to diagnose, treat, cure or prevent any disease or for the prescription of any medication or treatment. While the information contained may be of use in other jurisdictions, these materials were provided and designed for use in Canada and you are solely responsible for ensuring suitability and permitted use in other jurisdictions.  

**Contact Information.** If you have any questions about this Agreement or any of its disclaimers, terms or conditions of use or general questions, please contact us using the contact information set out below:  

For information, questions, or complaints, please write to:  

> The Centre for Mental Health  
> UHN 610 University Avenue Toronto, ON, M5G 2C1  
> Telephone: 416-340-5309    

**Express Consent to Receiving Electronic Messages and Upgrades from UHN.** By using the App, I hereby expressly consent to receiving electronic messages from UHN (email), including alerts and reminders, information, notifications, requests for your feedback, commercial messages, and other communications from UHN and as well as any applicable software updates or upgrades.  

All electronic communication carries some risk. For more information on the nature of these risks please see www.uhn.ca.  

### CONDITIONS OF USE  

Without limiting the foregoing, you warrant and agree that your use of the Application shall not: (i) in any manner violate any applicable federal, provincial, local, or international law or regulation or contain any material that could give rise to any civil or criminal liability under applicable laws or regulations; (ii) in any manner violate the terms of use of any third-party website that is linked to the Application; (iii) involve, provide, or contribute any false, inaccurate, or misleading information; and (iv) promote any illegal activity or advocate, promote, or assist any unlawful act.  

### INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY RIGHTS AND FEEDBACK  

You understand and agree that the Application and its entire contents, features, and functionality, including, but not limited to, all information, software, code, text, displays, graphics, photographs, video, audio, design, presentation, selection, and arrangement, are owned by UHN, its licensors. UHN name and all related names, logos, designs, images, and slogans are trademarks of UHN or its affiliates or licensors. You must not use such marks without the prior written permission of UHN. Use of any such property, except as expressly authorized, shall constitute an infringement or violation of the rights of the property owner and may be a violation of federal or other laws and could subject the infringer to legal action.  

You may only use the Application for personal use. You shall not directly or indirectly reproduce, compile for an internal database, distribute, modify, create derivative works of, publicly display, publicly perform, republish, download, store or transmit any of the material on our Application, in any form or medium whatsoever. Users are not permitted to modify copies of any materials from this Application nor delete or alter any copyright, trademark, or other proprietary rights notices from copies of materials from this site. If you print off, copy or download any part of the Application in breach of this Agreement, your right to use the Application will cease immediately. You have no right, title, or interest in or to the Application or content on the Application, and all rights not expressly granted are reserved by UHN. Any feedback you provide for this Application and any user submissions shall be deemed non-confidential. We shall be to use such information on an unrestricted basis.  

### DISCLAIMER  

The information captured or contained in or presented from the Application is exclusively intended for capturing symptoms. If you rely on the Application or any of its content, you do so entirely at your own risk. Without limiting the foregoing, you acknowledge and agree that the Application, will be provided on an **as is** basis and no representation, warranty, expressed or implied, of any nature, statutory, by operation of law or otherwise, is made or intended by providing the Application or any information in connection therewith, including but not limited to warranties of performance, fitness for a particular purpose, noninfringement, or that the Application meets the requirements of any laws, rules, standards, or governmental specifications or will be accurate or error-free. We will not be responsible for your use of the Application or any reliance you place on any content from the Application without limitation of any kind. Maintenance or support of the Application is expressly disclaimed.  

### INDEMNIFICATION  

To the maximum extent permitted by applicable law, you agree to defend, indemnify, and hold harmless UHN, its affiliates, and their respective directors, officers, employees, agents, and contractors from and against any claims, liabilities, damages, judgments, awards, losses, costs, expenses, or fees arising out of or relating to your breach of this Agreement.  

### LIMITATION ON LIABILITY  

EXCEPT WHERE SUCH EXCLUSIONS ARE PROHIBITED BY LAW, UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCE WILL UHN, ITS AFFILIATES OR THEIR RESPECTIVE DIRECTORS, OFFICERS, EMPLOYEES, AGENTS, OR CONTRACTORS BE LIABLE FOR NEGLIGENCE, NEGLIGENT MISREPRESENTATION, FUNDAMENTAL BREACH, DAMAGES OF ANY KIND, UNDER ANY LEGAL THEORY, INCLUDING ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, CONSEQUENTIAL, OR PUNITIVE DAMAGES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, LOSS OF REVENUE, LOSS OF PROFITS, LOSS OF BUSINESS OR ANTICIPATED SAVINGS, LOSS OF USE, LOSS OF GOODWILL, LOSS OF DATA, AND WHETHER CAUSED BY TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE), BREACH OF CONTRACT, BREACH OF PRIVACY, OR OTHERWISE, ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH YOUR USE, OR INABILITY TO USE, OR RELIANCE ON, THE APPLICATION, ANY LINKED WEBSITES, NOR ANY APPLICATION CONTENT, MATERIALS, POSTING, OR INFORMATION THEREON.  

### GOVERNING LAW AND JURISDICTION  

This Agreement shall be interpreted under, and any action or claim arising from or related to the Application shall be brought in the courts of, and governed exclusively by, the laws of Ontario, Canada and the applicable laws of Canada applicable therein, without regard to its conflicts of laws principles. Unless prohibited by applicable law, you expressly waive the right to participate in a class action proceeding.  

### MODIFICATIONS  

UHN reserves the right to update or change information contained in the Application without prior notice or prior acceptance.  

### COLLECTION, USE AND DISCLOSURE OF DATA  

a) **Transmission of data to UHN.** The Application collects data (user metrics), which is transmitted back to us through the Application regarding the use of the Application in order to better understand use of the Application and to help us identify areas for improvement. If you do not consent to the transmission of this data to UHN, then you must not use the Application.  

b) **Transmission of anonymized or aggregated data to Matomo Analytics.** The Application collects data, including Personal Health Information (PHI), through the Application regarding the use of the Application in order to better understand use of the Application and to help us identify areas for improvement. If you do not consent to the transmission of this data, then you must not use the Application.  

c) **Transmission and Storage of Identifying Data and PHI.** The Application also collects the users' personal information and/or PHI including name (first name or pseudonym) and self-reported symptoms. This information is stored on the Application and also transferred to the DATA-PRO server. The DATA-PRO Servers are hosted at UHN. User data is only transferred to one server, which is the server from which the account was created. Information stored on UHN Servers is accessible by UHN authorized staff at these sites. More information can be found in the Application Privacy Policy.  

### DISCLAIMER  

THE APPLICATION TRANSMITS YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION AND PHI OVER THE INTERNET. INFORMATION TRANSMITTED OVER THE INTERNET MAY BE AT RISK OF INADVERTANT LOSS OR THEFT. UHN CANNOT GUARANTEE THE SECURITY OF ANY INFORMATION TRANSMITTED TO OR FROM THE APPLICATION. BY USING THE APPLICATION, YOU AGREE THAT YOUR ACCESS AND USE OF THE APPLICATION AND THE CONTENT, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO PERSONAL INFORMATION AND PHI, IS ENTIRELY AT YOUR OWN RISK AND LIABILITY. NOTE THAT THERE ARE ALTERNATIVE METHODS TO COMPLETE THE SURVEY IF YOU WOULD NOT LIKE TO PROCEED WITH THIS APPLICATION.  

### THIRD PARTY-SOFTWARE LICENSES  

Portions of this application are derived from various third party and Open Source Libraries.  

### SEVERABILITY  

If any term or provision of this Agreement is invalid, illegal, or unenforceable in any jurisdiction, such invalidity, illegality, or unenforceability shall not affect any other term or provision of this Agreement.  

### ENTIRE AGREEMENT  

This Agreement and applicable UHN policies and procedures constitute the sole and entire agreement between you and UHN regarding the Application and supersedes all prior and contemporaneous understandings, agreements, representations and warranties, both written and oral, regarding such subject matter.  

### DATA-PRO PRIVACY POLICY  

This privacy policy governs your use of the software application DATA-PRO (**Application**) that was created by the UHN. DATA-PRO assists patients in reporting their symptoms and other health-related data to their healthcare providers. Based on the data you enter and the status of your health, you will get feedback and self-care instructions. It is not intended to replace your current care, but to supplement it with additional support.  

#### What information does the Application collect and how is it used?  

**User Provided Information.** The Application obtains the information you provide when you download and register with the Application.  

When you register with us and use the Application, you generally provide (a) email address, password and other registration information; (b) information about your condition, which may include self-reported symptom information and (c) information you provide us when you contact us for technical help with the application. UHN may also use your contact information (phone or email) to share important information about the Application and required updates.  

**Automatically Collected Information.** In addition, the Application may collect certain information automatically, including, but not limited to, the type of mobile device you use, your mobile devices unique device ID, the IP address of your mobile device, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile Internet browsers you use, and information about the way you use the Application.  

#### Do third parties see and/or have access to information obtained by the Application?  

Only aggregated, anonymized data is periodically transmitted to external services to help us improve the Application and our service. We will share your information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We may disclose User Provided and Automatically Collected Information:  
* As required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process;  
* With our trusted services providers who work on our behalf, do not have an independent use of the information we disclose to them, and have agreed to adhere to the rules set forth in this privacy statement and the Personal Health Information Protection Act, 2004 and any subsequent amendments.  

**Use of your Information by your Health Care Team.**  The information you enter into this Application will be provided to your healthcare team and will become part of your medical record.  

#### What are my rights?  

You can stop all collection of information by the Application easily by uninstalling the Application. You may use the standard uninstall processes as may be available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network. You may also close your account through the application.  

#### Data Retention Policy, Managing Your Information  

We will retain User provided data for an undetermined period of time based on our retention policy. For example. For the purposes of a research trial, your data will be stored for 10 years as per the Records Retention and Destruction Policy at UHN.  

#### Security  

We are concerned about safeguarding the confidentiality of your information. We provide reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect information we process and maintain. For example, we reasonably limit access to this information to authorized employees and contractors who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our Application.  

#### Changes  

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time for any reason. We will notify you of any changes to our Privacy Policy by posting the new Privacy Policy here and informing you via the application. You are advised to consult this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes, as continued use is deemed approval of all changes.  

#### Contact us  

For more detailed information about who sees your information and about your choices contact the Privacy Office.  

> UHN Privacy Office:  
> Telephone: 416-340-4800 ext. 6937  
> Email: privacy@uhn.ca  
> Website: http://www.uhn.ca/PatientsFamilies/Patient_Safety_Advocacy/Privacy/Pages/privacy_policy.aspx  

#### Complaints  

If you have complaints about UHN's compliance with this privacy policy or PHIPA, please contact UHN's Privacy Office at the above contact information. Further questions and concerns can be directed to the Office of the Information and Privacy Commissioner of Ontario at:  
> Office of the Information and Privacy Commissioner of Ontario  
> 2 Bloor Street East Suite 1400 Toronto, ON M4W 1A8  
> Phone: 1-800-387-0073  
> Website: www.ipc.on.ca
        </value>
        <type>String</type>
    </property>

</node>
