<!--
  Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
  or more contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file
  distributed with this work for additional information
  regarding copyright ownership.  The ASF licenses this file
  to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the
  "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance
  with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

  http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
  software distributed under the License is distributed on an
  "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
  KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
  specific language governing permissions and limitations
  under the License.
-->

<node>
    <name>TermsOfUse</name>
    <property>
        <name>title</name>
        <value>ePRO Terms of Use and Privacy Policy</value>
        <type>String</type>
    </property>
    <property>
        <name>version</name>
        <value>2022-03-02</value>
        <type>String</type>
    </property>
    <property>
        <name>acceptanceRequired</name>
        <value>True</value>
        <type>Boolean</type>
    </property>
    <property>
        <name>text</name>
        <value>

## ePRO Terms of Use

By using or accessing the DATA-PRO Application (“**ePRO**”), you agree to these Terms (“**Terms**”). These Terms are a legal agreement between you and the University Health Network (“**UHN**”). If you do not agree to all of these Terms, do not use the application and do not submit the survey through the application. Note that there are alternative methods to complete the survey if you would not like to use this application.  If you do use the application, relying on any information you see in the application is solely at your own risk. 

**The information provided in ePRO is not a substitute for the advice from your care provider. Always seek the advice from your care provider for any questions you may have about your medical symptoms or condition. Never disregard professional medical advice or delay in seeking it because of something you have read in the application.  Never delay obtaining medical advice or disregard medical advice because of something you have or have not read on the App.**

**If you think you have a medical or psychiatric emergency, call 911 or go to the nearest hospital.**

### What these Terms will tell you:

1. The purpose of ePRO
2. Limits of ePRO 
3. Your Responsibilities
4. How we Protect your Privacy
5. How to get your Questions Answered

### 1. Purpose of ePRO

This section describes the reasons that ePRO was created, which are the same as the services (“**Services**”) offered to you by UHN.

The main purpose of ePRO is to act as an information collection tool for physicians to better prepare for appointments with patients and to improve record keeping.  The Application is intended to facilitate symptom reporting to healthcare providers, to support quality monitoring and improvement, and general patient education relative to symptom status.  The information collected from you through ePRO will only be used for the purposes described here.  Most of the information you will be asked to provide through the surveys is being collected by UHN to support the provision of your care and to give you general symptom status information.  Some of the information being collected will be used specifically to assess the quality of our program at UHN and to support its improvement.  

In future your data may be further used to improve services at UHN or for research purposes, where such research is approved by a Research Ethics Board.  UHN takes your privacy seriously.  To learn more about UHN’s privacy practices please see the following pamphlet: [Privacy At the University Health Network](https://www.uhn.ca/PatientsFamilies/Health_Information/Health_Topics/Documents/Privacy_at_UHN.pdf).

#### Collection, Use and Disclosure of Data 
a) **Transmission of non-Identifying data to UHN**. The Application collects data (user metrics), which is transmitted back to UHN through the Application.  The information that is collected is aggregate and anonymous data relating to the use of the Application (e.g., number of users accessing the Application per day, the number of surveys submitted, etc.) in order for UHN to better understand use of the Application and to help us identify areas for improvement. If you do not consent to the transmission of this data to UHN, then you must not use ePRO.  

b) **Transmission and Storage of Identifying Data and PHI**. The Application also collects the users' personal information and/or PHI including name (first name or pseudonym) and self-reported symptoms. This information is stored on the Application and also transferred to the DATA-PRO server. The DATA-PRO Servers are hosted at University Health Network. Information stored on UHN Servers is accessible by UHN authorized staff at these sites. More information can be found in the Application Privacy Policy. 

### 2. Limits of ePRO

The ePRO App is not a medical device. Nothing contained in ePRO should be construed, directly or indirectly, as the practice of medicine or providing medical advice or medical services by UHN. The Application is not intended to diagnose, cure, mitigate, treat, or prevent disease or other conditions.  

All information provided to you in ePRO is provided for your information only. This means that: 
- Use of ePRO is not a substitute for professional medical advice, diagnosis or treatment.  If you have or suspect you have a health problem, please consult your care provider. 
- If you have or suspect you are experiencing a health emergency, please call 911 or visit the nearest Emergency Department in your area.

The ePRO App and content are provided are on an “as is” basis. This means that: 
- While UHN will take all steps it considers to be reasonable in making sure that your information is protected, accurate and available to you, UHN assumes no liability for a delay, failure, inaccuracy, interruption or corruption of any information transmitted via ePRO. 
- UHN reserves the right to change, suspend or deactivate ePRO at any time. 
- UHN reserves the right to change these Terms at any time and will make these changes available to you the next time you access ePRO. Using ePRO after these changes have been made means that you agree to the changes. 

#### No Regulatory Approval

ePRO has not been evaluated by Health Canada, the United States Food and Drug Administration (USFDA) or any other domestic or foreign regulatory agency and is not approved to diagnose, treat, cure or prevent any disease or for the prescription of any medication or treatment. While the information contained may be of use in other jurisdictions, these materials were provided and designed for use in Canada and you are solely responsible for ensuring suitability and permitted use in other jurisdictions.  

### 3. Your Rights and Responsibilities

You received the email containing your link to ePRO because you consented to the use of email by UHN to communicate with you about your care.  If you change your mind and no longer want to receive emails about ePRO, or any emails from UHN, it is your responsibility to let us know.  To communicate this instruction, contact your care provider and/or the UHN Privacy Office at the contact information below.

While the information you are asked to provide through the survey is being used to support your care and for quality improvement, you are not required to complete the survey. You may refuse to complete the survey and you will still be able to receive care from UHN.  Your clinician may ask you the same or similar questions to those in the survey at your scheduled appointment if you have not submitted the survey.

Once you have decided to use ePRO and start completing your survey information, it is your responsibility to protect it. UHN is not liable for breaches that result from you not taking the following steps to protect your information. By using the ePRO, you agree to take these steps:
- Ensure that no one is “shoulder-surfing” or watching you when viewing or adding in your information. 
    - You agree to choose more private spaces (like your home) over public ones (like on public transportation). 
    - You agree to not use a public computer to access ePRO (like in a library). 
    - You agree to not use free and/or untrusted Wi-Fi to access the ePRO survey.
- Only use the Patient Education material provided to you via ePRO for your personal, non-commercial use 
    - You agree that it is your responsibility to protect materials that you download, because someone who finds them could make conclusions about your health from the content of the materials.
    - You agree that any other use of the Patient Education material is strictly prohibited without written permission. 
- Tell your care provider or the UHN Privacy Office (contact information below) about any suspicious activity so we can investigate it. During an investigation an audit may be done of those who accessed your information. Malicious activity will be addressed according to hospital policy and/or as permitted by law.

You can learn more about your privacy rights at the UHN Privacy website (see below).

> **UHN Privacy Office**  
> Telephone: 416-340-4800 ext. 6937  
> Email: privacy@uhn.ca  
> Website: http://www.uhn.ca/PatientsFamilies/Patient_Safety_Advocacy/Privacy/Pages/privacy_policy.aspx  

### 4. How we Protect your Privacy

In collecting and using your personal health information in ePRO, UHN must follow the rules set out in the Personal Health Information Protection Act. UHN must also follow the rules set out in the Freedom of Information &amp; Protection of Privacy Act, which applies to administrative type information that does not identify you (such as the number of users). 

UHN takes steps to make sure that your information is safeguarded by meeting best practice standards for security. UHN has individuals who review any potential changes to the App to make sure that the changes are lawful and protect your privacy to the best of our ability. A privacy review, security review and Vulnerability Test were completed by experts in their fields to ensure that legal requirements are met and best practices are followed. Key functions of ePRO are regularly reviewed and checked, and changes are made where necessary. UHN has taken steps to make sure that information is backed up, updated regularly and is available to you when you need it. 

Your information will not be made available by UHN to anyone other than your care provider and the designated individuals at UHN who have the responsibility to maintain this Application and are trained and overseen to make sure that they do not use or disclose any of your information inappropriately.

### 5. How to get your Questions Answered
If you have any questions about this document, general questions about how to use ePRO, or if you have other questions or concerns please contact us using the contact information set out below:  

For information, questions, or complaints, please contact:

> **Peter Munk Cardiac Centre**  
> 585 University Avenue Toronto, ON, M5G 2N2  
> Telephone: 1-888-846-4278

> **The Centre for Mental Health**  
> UHN 610 University Avenue Toronto, ON, M5G 2C1  
> Telephone: 416-340-5309

### Limitation of Liability 

EXCEPT WHERE SUCH EXCLUSIONS ARE PROHIBITED BY LAW, UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCE WILL UHN, ITS AFFILIATES OR THEIR RESPECTIVE DIRECTORS, OFFICERS, EMPLOYEES, AGENTS, OR CONTRACTORS BE LIABLE FOR NEGLIGENCE, NEGLIGENT MISREPRESENTATION, FUNDAMENTAL BREACH, DAMAGES OF ANY KIND, UNDER ANY LEGAL THEORY, INCLUDING ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, CONSEQUENTIAL, OR PUNITIVE DAMAGES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, LOSS OF REVENUE, LOSS OF PROFITS, LOSS OF BUSINESS OR ANTICIPATED SAVINGS, LOSS OF USE, LOSS OF GOODWILL, LOSS OF DATA, AND WHETHER CAUSED BY TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE), BREACH OF CONTRACT, BREACH OF PRIVACY, OR OTHERWISE, ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH YOUR USE, OR INABILITY TO USE, OR RELIANCE ON, THE APPLICATION, ANY LINKED WEBSITES, NOR ANY APPLICATION CONTENT, MATERIALS, POSTING, OR INFORMATION THEREON.  

### Indemnity 

To the maximum extent permitted by applicable law, you agree to defend, indemnify, and hold harmless UHN, its affiliates, and their respective directors, officers, employees, agents, and contractors from and against any claims, liabilities, damages, judgments, awards, losses, costs, expenses, or fees arising out of or relating to your breach of this Agreement. 

**Copyright © DATA Team**  
**Date Last Revised: March 2, 2022**

---

## DATA-PRO Privacy Policy

This privacy policy governs your use of the software application ePRO (**Application**) that was created by the UHN. EPRO assists patients in reporting their symptoms and other health-related data to their healthcare providers. Based on the data you enter and the status of your health, you will get feedback and self-care information. This information is not intended to replace your current care, but to supplement it with additional education.  

### What information does the Application collect and how is it used?  

**User Provided Information**. The Application obtains the information you provide when you complete and submit the ePRO surveys.  

When you participate in the use of ePRO, you provide consent for UHN to (a) to send you emails for this program and generally related to your care; (b) collect your email address; (c) collect information about your condition, which may include self-reported symptom information and (d) information you provide us when you contact us for technical help with the application. 

UHN may also use your contact information (phone or email) to share important information about the Application and required updates.  

**Automatically Collected Information**. In addition, the Application may collect certain anonymous information automatically, including, but not limited to statistics about the way you use the Application (e.g., how often you use the link to complete and submit a survey).  Your statistical information will be aggregated with other peoples’ metrics and included as an overall count – your individual information will not be identifiable. 

### Do third parties see and/or have access to information obtained by the Application? 

Only aggregated, anonymized data is periodically transmitted to external services to help us improve the Application and our service. We only share your information with third parties in ways that are described in this privacy statement. We may disclose User Provided and Automatically Collected Information:  
- As required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process;  
- With our trusted services providers who work on our behalf, and who do not have an independent use of the information we disclose to them, and have agreed to adhere to the rules set forth in this privacy statement and the Personal Health Information Protection Act, 2004 and any subsequent amendments.  

**Use of your Information by your Health Care Team**.  The information you enter into this Application will be provided to your healthcare team and will become part of your medical record.  

### What are my rights?

You can stop all collection of information via the surveys by not using ePRO.  To prevent receipt of additional ePRO-related emails, you can use the unsubscribe button in the emails you have already received.  The unsubscribe feature will prevent you from receiving future emails from ePRO, but not all emails from UHN.

### Data Retention Policy, Managing Your Information  
Your ePRO User Provided data will become part of your health record, and will be retained for an undetermined period of time based on our UHN retention policy. For example, if you agree to participate in a research trial, your data will be stored for 10 years as per the Records Retention and Destruction Policy at UHN.  

### Security  
We are concerned about safeguarding the confidentiality of your information. We provide reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect information we process and maintain. For example, we reasonably limit access to this information to authorized employees and contractors who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our Application.  

### Changes  
This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time for any reason. We will notify you of any changes to our Privacy Policy by posting the new Privacy Policy here and informing you via the application. You are advised to consult this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes, as continued use is deemed approval of all changes.  

### Contact us  
For more detailed information about who sees your information and about your choices contact the Privacy Office 

> **UHN Privacy Office**  
> Telephone: 416-340-4800 ext. 6937  
> Email: privacy@uhn.ca  
> Website: http://www.uhn.ca/PatientsFamilies/Patient_Safety_Advocacy/Privacy/Pages/privacy_policy.aspx  

### Complaints  
If you have complaints about UHN's compliance with this privacy policy or PHIPA, please contact UHN's Privacy Office at the above contact information. Further questions and concerns can be directed to the Office of the Information and Privacy Commissioner of Ontario at:  

> **Office of the Information and Privacy Commissioner of Ontario**  
> 2 Bloor Street East Suite 1400 Toronto, ON M4W 1A8  
> Phone: 1-800-387-0073  
> Website: www.ipc.on.ca
        </value>
        <type>String</type>
    </property>

</node>
